Slavic mss., 1817-1947 LMC 1980
Lilly Library
Slavic mss.
1817-1947
Lilly Library
LMC 1980
3 Boxes 2 standard, 1 custom
1 bound
The Slavic mss., 1817-1947, consists of letters and documents of Russian and Czech political and literary figures, including Russian author Ivan Alekseevich Bunin, 1870-1953, and Czech politicians Tomáš Garrigue Masaryk, 1850-1937, and Jan Garrigue Masaryk, 1886-1948.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transfer: 1980-1981; Purchase: 2005
Biographical Note
Tomáš Garrigue Masaryk, 1850-1937, was a Czech politician, sociologist, philosopher, and first President of Czechoslovokia.
Jan Garrigue Masaryk, 1886-1948, was a Czech diplomat, politician, and Foreign Minister of Czechoslovakia (1940-1948).
Ivan Alekseevich Bunin, 1870-1953, was the first Russian writer awarded the Nobel Prize for Literature.
Peter II, 1715-1730, was Emperor of Russia (1727-1730).
Alexander I, 1777-1825, was Emperor of Russia (1801-1825).
Nicholas I, 1796-1855, was Emperor of Russia (1825-1855).
Scope and Content Note
The Slavic mss., 1817-1947, consists of letters and documents of Russian and Czech political and literary figures, including Russian author Ivan Alekseevich Bunin, 1870-1953, and Czech politicians Tomáš Garrigue Masaryk, 1850-1937, and Jan Garrigue Masaryk, 1886-1948.
Slavs; České Budějovice (Czech Republic); Russia; Nicholas I, Emperor of Russia, 1796-1855; Alexander I, Emperor of Russia, 1777-1825; Peter II, Emperor of Russia, 1715-1730; Masaryk, Jan, 1886-1948; Masaryk, T. G. (Tomáš Garrigue), 1850-1937; Bunin, Ivan Alekseevich, 1870-1953
- Slavic mss.
  - (folio). Alexander I. Certificate of promotion..., 1817 (Bound 1)
  - (facsimile - folio). Peter II. [the mountain wreath], n.d.
  - Nezval, Viteslav. Poem and photograph., 1956, June 24
  - Petr Bezruč. Siezskě pisně., 1942
  - Hitchcock, Edward B. "He Was My Friend": The Story of Jan Masaryk.
  - Volume of Poetry by Dr. Fr. Prešéren., 1846, June 10
  - Slavic papers (Box 1)
    - Volume. Rodokmen, Vladimira Vaška. (Box 1)
    - Volume. A. Sova/Rukopisy. (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Tomáš Garrigue. To "Your Excellency.", 1900, Mar. 28 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Tomáš Garrigue. To [?], 1895, Oct. 20 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Tomáš Garrigue. To Gruber, Josef., 1907, Jan. 16 (Box 1)
    - Yudin, A. [?]. To [?]., 1919, Dec. 26 (Box 1)
    - Bunin, I.A. To his publisher., 1921 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Tomáš Garrigue. To Fondu legioná..., 1920, Apr. 22 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Jan Garrigue. To Templewood, Samuel J.G. Hoare, 1st viscount., 1938, Oct. 14 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Jan Garrigue. To Ministerstvu zahranicnich veci, [Prague]., 1938, Oct. 14 (Box 1)
    - Masaryk, Jan Garrigue. "Ani opona, ani most...", 1947, Mar. 20 (Box 1)
    - Bunin, I.A. Neskol'ko slov angliis-komu pisateliu., n.d. (Box 1)
    - Bunin, I.A. O Gorkom., n.d. (Box 1)
    - Kuprin, A.I. Leinn: opyt kharak-teristiki., n.d. (Box 1)
    - Kuprin, A.I. Pro drugoe., n.d. (Box 1)
    - Remizov, A.M. iz knigi "zviezda dadzviez dnaia.", n.d. (Box 1)
    - Envelope of two coins bearing likeness of Masaryk, Tomáš Garrigue. (Box 1)
  - (folio). Nicholas I. Certificate of promotion..., 1826 (Box 3)